

## Tuğhan Belbek

# Software Development Technology Manager @ Koç Sistem

- **+90 553 265 82 67**
- tbelbek.com
- in linkedin.com/in/tbelbek

## Summary

Currently managing digital product development and high-level project road mapping, Agile and DevOps transformation processes as well as leading team up to 25 people.

Full-stack developer with 8+ years of experience with C# and 6+ with JavaScript. Preference for back-end development. Key projects include development of warehouse management system using GPS location system (KocSystem) and development of public transformation solutions which include car PCs, embedded canbus, and server side (Antasya Software Consultancy).

C#, C++ Developer, Team Lead, Mentor, Presenter and Instructor, Registered SCRUM Master, Ex-athlete.

## Work experience

## **Software Development Technology Manager**

01-07-2021 - Present

#### KoçSistem

#### **KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- · Digital product management
- Development tasks (around 50%)
- Leading team (up to 25 people)
- · High level road mapping
- Process/Agile management
- DevOps management
- Taking part in HR employee experience project
- Mentoring and leading employees to develop career in software development
- · Performing presenter/moderator tasks on company's wide live events

KEY TECHNOLOGIES USED: .NET Core, C#, MVC, Git, Azure

**KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**: Completing the first year of the roadmap I created how to convert existing technology and infrastructure to a modern version, including devops, security, project architecture and also agile maturity.

As a Technology Manager;

- 4 Key Metrics implementation in DevSecOps completed %75
- 0 Security Flaws
- 2x Product Release Rate
- Test frameworks implementation
- Database automation implementation
- AGILE maturity increased from 3,1/4 to 3,7/4

## **Software Development Lead**

01-03-2020 - 01-07-2021

## KoçSistem

#### **KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Responsible for team's planning, performance, technical leading
- Architectural support to projects
- Frontier on DevOps transformation, code quality measure metrics implementation, Agile transformation, integration management, app ecosystem management.

KEY TECHNOLOGIES USED: .NET Core, C#, MVC, Git, Azure

**KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**: Creating road map how to convert existing technology and infrastructure to a modern version, including devops, security, project architecture and also agile maturity.

As a team lead:

- Git transformation, branch, PR and Code Review strategies implemented,
- %60 decreased SLA rate
- DevOps implementation of all applications on Azure
- %55 decrease in bugs in new features released
- User satisfaction increased %50 percent

#### **Senior Software Developer**

13-03-2018 - 29-02-2020

#### **KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Developing warehouse management system using GPS location system including:
  - · Card access administration
  - o Factory production band audit and management
  - Truck tracing
- Providing leading support about software architecture and solution development in the team.
- Consultant to KocSistem Business Partners in Turkey and around the world like Arcelik, Beko, Bosch Siemens Hausgerate, Aygaz.

**KEY TECHNOLOGIES USED**: Visual Basic, .net Core 3.0, C#, various ORM tools (Dapper, EF), Redis, Elastic Search, RabbitMQ, MVC, Git, Azure, GPS location system

**KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**: Some of the developed modules were added as a contribution to company-wide in the project framework of KocSistem. One project received an award in 2019 IDC Awards and a Customer Satisfaction Award in Turkey.

- Contribution to company wide framework
- 2 Award in one project

#### **Senior Software Developer**

12-12-2016 - 12-03-2018

#### Antasya Software & Consultancy

#### **KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Developing public transport solutions in C# and C++
- Working with IETT (Istanbul public transport agency) and Modyo (The company who is running the in-car and intrain advertisement signage solution)
- Performing research about the "Green stop project" which is about E-Ink screens and solar power with embedded pcs in stops to provide info and also media content to customers(In this case, passengers.)
- Worked at the final edge of the new version of digital signage solution of "Modyo" company.
- Developing Web UI with MVC framework and devices with Android 4.4

KEY TECHONOLOGIES USED: C++, .NET, C#, MVC, Git, Jenkins, Azure

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS: Created a new AVL solution for IETT and Malatya Municipality

#### **Software Consultant**

27-08-2014 - 12-12-2016

BilgeAdam Corporate Consultancy Company

#### **KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- Consultancy an Technical support for top 500 companies like Borusan, Koçsistem, Kordsa, Medical part etc int 10+ projects.
- Projects developed were in diverse areas: Stock Management, Public activity planning, In house resource and talent management, Health services management with patient services

KEY TECHNOLOGIES USED: .NET C#, MVC C#, JavaScript

## **Education**

#### Management of IT Systems

2016 - 2018

Beykent University, Istanbul

Master's Degree, Science

Physics 2008 - 2014

Marmara University, Istanbul

Bachelor's Degree, Science

PROGRAMMING	competencies (1 - Basic, 10 - Ac	_
LANGUAGES:	.Net Core	9
	C++	6
	JavaScript	8
	Java	1
	Python	2
TECHNOLOGIES:	MVC	9
	HTML5	8
	Restful Services	9
	Microservices	6
	Dapper	6
	React.js	2
	Qt Framework	4
	PL/SQL	5
	Embedded Systems	4
	Google Maps API	5
	Azure DevOps	7
	CI/CD	7
	Jenkins	4
OTHER:	Agile	7
	Scrum	8
	Waterfall	7
	Web Development	9
	Linux	7
<b>Professional Training</b>	${f g}$ and Acquired Certificates $-$	
Registered Scrum Master, S	Scrum Inc, Nov 2021	
	Sept 2021 (a set of 5 certificates: Agile Leadershi zation; Agile Leadership; Agile Leadership Capstor	
Introduction to Software Pro	oduct Management, Coursera, Sept 2021	
Communication Strategies	<b>for a Virtual Age</b> , Aug 2021	
Leadership in 21rst Century	, Coursera, Aug 2021	
How to Manage a Remote T	<b>eam</b> , Coursera, Jul 2021	
Mentorship Skills Workshop	o, Qmark Danışmanlık A.Ş., June 2021	
Shaping up with Angular, Co	ode School, Aug 2015	
MS: Programming in C#, Mi	crosoft, Jul 2015	
MCPS: Microsoft Certified I	Professional, Microsoft, Apr 2015	
MS: Programming in HTML	5 with JavaScript and CSS3, Microsoft Apr 2015	
Languages		
	Native/C2	
English Full professional proficiency/C1		